Srivas Chennu

srivaschennu.github.io +44 7828 90 66 92 srivas@gmail.com

The image part with relationship ID rid2 was not found in the file.

Profile

I specialise in translating the latest machine learning and statistical inference methods into scalable real-world applications in industry and academia. I have 14+ years of R&D experience, and a background in computer science. My research has been featured by the BBC, Wired Magazine, New Scientist and Discovery Channel. I have worked as a consultant and as a software engineer.

Employment

2019-present Senior Machine Learning Scientist Apple, UK Developed large-scale deep learning and gradient boosting models for behavioural prediction Designed and deployed adaptive reinforcement learning based on probabilistic statistical inference Assistant Professor University of Kent, UK 2016-2019 Led health care AI project to predict biomarkers of consciousness from time series data 2010-2016 Senior Research Associate University of Cambridge, UK Developed statistical, ML and time series models for healthcare technology applications in neurology The Alan Turing Institute, UK Visiting Researcher 2018 2002-2004 Member of Technical Staff **Oracle Corporation, India**

• Software engineer in the Oracle Reports team, a part of Oracle's Internet Application Server platform

Research

- Co-author of 50+ peer-reviewed publications in academic journals; <u>h-index of 26</u> (as of 2022)
- · On deep learning, reinforcement learning, computational neuroscience and Bayesian inference

Consulting

DataTiger (Marketing optimisation startup acquired by Apple)

2018

· Applied ensemble machine learning for forecasting dynamics of customer behaviour

Rsrchxchange (FinTech startup)

2017

- · Built neural network-based NLP model for content similarity analysis of financial research reports
- Developed latent factor models with Apache Spark to build financial research recommender models

Education

PhD in Computer Science	University of Kent, Canterbury, UK	2006-2009
MSc in Information and Communication Systems	Hamburg University of Technology Hamburg, Germany	2004-2006
BEng in Computer Science and Engineering	Visveswaraiah Technological University Bangalore, India	1998-2002

Skills

- Big Data Modelling, Machine Learning
- Parametric, Non-parametric and Bayesian Statistics
- · Data Science and Visualisation
- Signal Processing and Time Series Analysis
- · Graph Theory and Network Analysis
- **Tools**: tensorflow, pytorch, scipy, pandas, pyspark
- · Deep Neural Networks
- Applied Artificial Intelligence
- · Research Methods in Neuroscience
- · Computer Networking and Security
- Operating Systems
- Languages: Python, JAVA, C++, C